morningstar.ca 2014-02-09

# Morningstar: Mutual fund investing, analysis, research, ratings and news

**Privacy Policy – Our Commitment to Your Privacy**

Your privacy is very important to us. At Morningstar we want to make Your experience with us satisfying and safe.

This Privacy Policy outlines the types of information we gather from Your use of the product, how we use it, with whom we might share it, the means by which we keep it secure, and the choices You have about the information You choose to share with us.

Morningstar designs its products to help You make the best possible investment decisions. We are committed to providing independent, insightful investment information. We want You to be able to take advantage of Morningstar’s tools and information with complete confidence. 

Every time we send You an e-mail communication, information on how to stop receiving e-mail from Morningstar is included. Please follow these instructions to stop specific emails from coming to You.

If You have further questions about our privacy practices or this Privacy Policy, please contact us at: [caprivacypolicy@morningstar.com](mailto:caprivacypolicy@morningstar.com)

**Personal Information We Collect**

The types of personal information we collect depend on the product or service You (“You”) receive from us. This information may include, but is not limited to:

  * Your name, phone number, physical and email address
  * Your credit card number
  * Your demographic information, such as age, income range, investment preferences, etc
  * Stock and fund information (e.g., stock or fund ticker symbols), if You create a personalized portfolio, as well as financial information relating to the stocks or funds You track.

**Personal Information – Why We Collect It**

Morningstar may collect certain personal information to provide You with investment information and tools, to perform marketing and research related activities, to supply other administrative services (e.g., set up new accounts), to respond to inquiries, etc. In addition, we may from time to time, review Your usage of the site to be able to better provide You with information about products and services that we believe may be of interest to You.

**Personal Information – How We Collect It**

The personal information we collect may be captured from a variety of sources. These sources include, but are not limited to:

  * Voluntary submissions (e.g., responses to surveys, requests for information on our products or those of our advertisers/marketing partners)
  * Registrations/Applications to receive products or services
  * Reviews of site usage patterns

**Use and Access of Your Personal Information With Others**

As a general rule, Morningstar will not make the personal information gathered using Morningstar.ca available to anyone outside of Morningstar and its affiliates – except as instructed by You or where required to comply with law. Please note, however, that there are several exceptions to this policy. 

First, if we use service providers, these service providers may have access to Your personal information to perform contractually specified services on behalf of Morningstar or You. 

Second, if You indicate that You are interested in receiving information about a particular third party's products/services, or You opt to receive certain products or services through Morningstar, we may provide Your personal information to that third party for purposes of fulfilling Your request(s). 

With respect to service provider(s), Morningstar contractually requires that all personal information be kept confidential. Additionally, Morningstar takes reasonable steps to ensure that third parties receiving information about You at Your request maintain the confidentiality of that information. 

**Links to Other Web Sites**

Morningstar may provide links to one or more other Web sites. We encourage You to read their individual privacy policies before providing any of Your personal information to them. 

**Protection of Your Personal Information**

Morningstar puts reasonable security measures in place to protect against unauthorized access to, or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of personal information. These measures include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data. 

Morningstar operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided. 

**Use of Cookies**

Morningstar uses Cookies to set users’ preferences, gather basic tracking information (such as login and password), date, time of visit and preferences, and to monitor the presentation of our site. This information allows Morningstar to personalize Your experience when using our online products and services and improve the quality of our site navigation. Cookies do not reveal the identity of the individual user but only identify the computer utilized by that user. 

Please note that advertisers on our site may also deploy cookies and other technology to gather users’ basic site usage information (such as pages visited or frequency of visits) to measure and improve the effectiveness of their advertising. For more information regarding Advertisers’ practices, including how to opt-out of their cookie tracking, please visit the advertisers’ privacy policies. 

For more information regarding advertising network practices, including how to opt-out of their cookie tracking, please visit the ad network's privacy policy at: 

<http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>  
<http://advertising.aol.com/privacy>  
<http://casalemedia.com/privacy.html>  
<http://www.marchex.com/legal/privacy-statement.html>

For more information regarding ad serving network practices, including how to opt-out of their cookie tracking, please visit the ad server's privacy policy at: 

<http://www.zedo.com/company/privacy.htm>  
<http://mediaplex.com/MOJO_Privacy_Statement.shtml>  
<http://www.atlassolutions.com/privacy.aspx>  
<http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy.html>

For more information regarding the gathering of site usage information, including how to opt-out of their cookie tracking, please visit AudienceScience's privacy policy at: 

<http://audiencescience.com/privacy.asp>

**Accuracy of Your Personal Information**

You are responsible for periodically checking to ensure that Your personal information included in this site is updated and correct. 

**How to Update Your Personal Information**

If You desire to update any personal information, You may do so by accessing Morningstar.ca. 

**What About Children’s Privacy**

Morningstar does not separately identify, or collect, any information that is specific to children. 

**Your Consent**

By using Morningstar.ca, You consent to the collection and use of Your personal information and any related information in the manner described in this Privacy Policy.

**Changes to the Privacy Policy**

Morningstar reserves the right to change this Policy at any time by distributing and/or posting a new Privacy Policy without notice. We encourage You to review our Privacy Policy on a regular basis so that You will be aware of any changes to it. 

Last revised: August 2010
